JENNY DOLAN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jenniferdolan/ | email:brightvibesrock@gmail.com | Portsmouth NH & York, ME

SUMMARY

I have 15+ experience as a technical product leader with a successful track record building teams and capabilities to enable software engineering organizations to deliver performant, stable, and reliable experiences into the hands of digital customers. Recent business transformation initiative at CVS Health was awarded an excellence nomination and resulted in a 12X increase in production delivery, with every software release meeting security and implicit end-to-end reliability standards.

SKILLS

- Technical Product Mgmt
- Data Mmgt & Delivery
- DevSecOps

- iOS Mobile Development
- Technology Ops & Mgmt
- Web Development
- Cloud Infra Automation
- Talent Management
- Generative AI

EXPERIENCE

CVS Pharmacy Inc. | Lead Director, Product - IT Platform | Burlington, MA /Hybrid | 2020 - Present

- Collaborated with business executives and leaders of Aetna/CVS engineering, security, and
 architecture to provide exceptional developer experiences and full-stack technology platform
 capabilities which enables business delivery to more than 56 million digital health customers and
 greater than 1 million mobile CVS Pharmacy application downloads.
- Directed strategy and objectives and key results (OKRs) for the platform engineering team and alignment to the company's business goals.
- Managed a dozen technical product managers and defined common routines of communication outputs such as roadmaps, enterprise scorecards, product portals, monthly operating reports, tech bytes, product capability and developer experience (dX) assessments and feedback loops.
- Partnered with Enterprise Security to integrate supply chain security practices to the build and deploy
 pipeline. The self-service pipeline utilizes a github actions workflow that incorporates static code
 analysis, software composition analysis, container scanning, cosign, mobile scan, SBOM (Software
 Bill of Materials) generation and DAST (Dynamic Application Security Testing).

- Directed enablement of more than \$60 million in SaaS Infrastructure with seamless cloud platform integrations on GCP and AWS [GitHub, Circle CI, Harness, Jenkins, Argo CD, LaunchDarkly, Snyk, JFrog Artifactory, SonarCloud, Kubernetes, Confluent Kafka, Hashicorp Vault, iOS, Android, Akamai, Fastly, Grafana, OpsGenie, Jira, Slack, Apigee, Kong, Venafi, Backstage, Suse Rancher, GCP/AWS, Grafana, Grafana Loki, Otel, Prometheus, New Relic, Quantum]
- Directed product delivery and lifecycle for reusable workflows, infrastructure automation, quick starts and libraries to support web and mobile developers working with Angular, Java Spring boot, Nodejs, Next.js, React, iOS and Android.
- Partnered with legal team to file the first patent for CVS Developer Platform for an internally
 developed software solution that accelerates creation of secure APIs using standard patterns. CVS
 API-Forge platform centrally houses more than 1K business and about 300 external healthcare APIs.
 Patent is pending with the U.S. patent office.
- Launched the inauguration of CVS's first Developer Academy that focused on teaching developers
 and digital leadership how to improve speed to market, application quality and security posture by
 leveraging platform capabilities and employing modern software practices.
- Major enterprise accomplishment: Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery Modernization
 Initiative that was given an Excellence Award and achieved more than \$3 million in cost savings,
 resulted in transparency of application delivery metrics and 12X increase in production delivery via
 secure self-service pipeline (i.e. production deployments went from about 60 per week to 725 per
 week).

Entrepreneur | Freelance IT Consulting | 2018-Present

- Freelance IT Consulting to advise hedge fund/private equity firms on technology & companies.
- Manage/sell/rent/remodel properties in Reading MA, York ME, Ogunquit ME and Portsmouth NH.

Liberty Mutual Insurance - Global Retail Markets IT - Information Management Division | Senior Software Development - Application Portfolio Manager | Boston, MA & Dover, NH, 2012-2018

- Managed software engineering practice, technical resource operations and budget, capability frameworks, information security audit & compliance and staffing procurement of \$7M-\$10M across Dover NH, Boston MA, Seattle WA, India, Wausau, WI.
- Collaborated with the senior data architects and executive leadership to develop cross functional organizational frameworks to transform data engineering culture, tools, process, and skills landscape for about 24 Data Platform Scrum Teams.
- Portfolio delivery manager for division's AWS cloud enablement and digital data programs to move on-premise data warehouse to hybrid cloud solution using AWS for Right Track, Claims and Data Science. [Technologies: Java, IAM, S3, Glacier, Redshift, Athena, EMR, CyberArk, k8s]

- Directed DataOps transformation solutions for 100+ software engineers to provide critical data to >11K home and auto insurance customers saving the company millions and recognized for multiple IT Excellence, President and Bravo Nominations. [Technologies: Oracle Goldengate, Atlassian Bitbucket, IBM Watson, Jira, Java, Python, Unix, Informatica, Jenkins, JFrog Artifactory, Teradata, AWS Data Warehousing and Oracle Db.]
- Delivered the first on-demand automated data warehouse database deployment at the firm using open-source systems with development of secure micro service to handle authentication and authorization.
- Awarded Certificate for Innovation from Northeastern University as a Semi-Finalist in 2018 IOT
 Hackathon / produced a POC using augmented reality technology for a 4D video game. Participant in
 multiple Liberty Hackathons using Al/Sentiment Analysis, Telematics, Apple Watch and Fitbit to
 reduce insurance claims.

Cambridge Associates LLC - IT Division | Senior Technology Program Manager | Boston, MA, 2007 - 2011

- Head of PMO (Program Management Office) ~24 Staff and \$5M, residing in Arlington, VA and Boston, MA.
- Responsible for executive reporting of KPIs, Budget, Audit and Compliance (Internally Developed Software accounting).
- Product Owner for Investment Performance Reporting (Private Equity, Hedge Fund, Marketable), Accounting and Client Relationship Management product teams.
- Established SCRUM methodologies and implemented tools/framework to support agile development processes using Microsoft Team Foundation System and Source Code Management.
- Instituted a secure platform to manage NPPI data and investor vetting (Complinet).
- Provided technical expertise for directing test automation and software quality initiatives for the firm's investment office applications.

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

Northeastern University, Boston, MA / Dual Bachelor of Science – Economics & Geology, CVS Safe - PO/PM Training, Fastly CDN Academy, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform - DevOps, Udemy - iOS Bootcamp, Udemy - Web Developer Bootcamp and Github Actions Training, Coursera - Generative AI

CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Academy (PMA) Certification, MIT Sloan School - Marketing Analytics Certification, Project Management Professional 2011 exp, Scrum Alliance – Certified Scrum Master, ASTQB Certified Software Test Manager